"Frame 3: Climate informed governance, management advice, and tools"	Category	"Near term (e.g., annual) tactical decision making"	"Near term (e.g., annual) strategic decision making"	"Med-Long term (e.g., multi year to decadal) strategic decision making"	order
Section in single stock advice which highlights/catagorises climate related vulnerability of stock	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"	x			16
Management strategy evaluation (MSE)	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"		x	x	82
Maps of anticipated changes per species	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"		x		40
Fisheries Adaptation Status Evaluation (science tool to operationalize climate risk)	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"			x	90
Retrospective analysis for exploring past impacts	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"			x	81
Vulnerability / risk assessments (indicator based approach)	"Climate impacts, vulnerability, and risk assessments"			x	71
Executive summaries	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	9
Infographics and maps to help visualise the concepts and uncertainties	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	13
Media & Visualizations	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	5
Policy briefs or report cards	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	6
Secondary/primary school educational workshops	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	15
Visual tools/storytelling/cartoons	Communication & knowledge sharing	x	x	x	14
regional climate-change effect summary sheets; based on stock assessments (past) and/or projections	Communication & knowledge sharing	x			22
Social media (use of twitter etc for knowledge transfer)	Communication & knowledge sharing	x			8
"Interactive information tool to enable users to evaluate CO2, catch potential, and other outcomes of different gear choices"	Communication & knowledge sharing		x	x	61
"Web-type portal for displaying evidence, sharing data"	Communication & knowledge sharing		x	x	51
xVisual tools/storytelling/cartoons	Communication & knowledge sharing				28
"xCo-production of knowledge (field, gear, etc)"	duplicate				12
"xCo-production of knowledge (field, gear, etc)"	duplicate				88
"Cerification, scoring, carbon labeling, ecolabeling"	Incentives & finance	x	x		25
"Emergency financing, relief, insurance"	Incentives & finance	x			19
Need a more transparent process for ranking/scoring certification and labelling and need certification with specific targets associated with them	Incentives & finance	x			4
Weighted extra quota for harvesters using more CO2 friendly gears	Incentives & finance	x			21
"Financial incentives for technology and gear development (e.g., loans)"	Incentives & finance		x	x	45
Incentive through lower CO2 taxation	Incentives & finance		x		36
"Climate conditioned risk advice - ie incorporating the uncertainty associated with climate effects on a fish stock by ""buffering"" advice. (Science tool to operationlaize climate risk)"	pink	x			18
"Integrate targets (e.g. IPCC and IPBES) into models and forecasting (e.g. stock assessments, MSEs)"	pink			x	96
"Co-production of knowledge (field, gear, etc)"	Process for climate informed advice	x	x	x	47
Science workshops	Process for climate informed advice	x	x	x	27
Workshops with industry	Process for climate informed advice	x			24
"""Companion modelling""/serious game/workshop"	Process for climate informed advice		x	x	63
Gaming / scenario exploration	Process for climate informed advice		x	x	58
Participatory and co-development scenario planning	Process for climate informed advice		x	x	48
"Serious games (something that stakeholders and others can ""play"" with - table top and also computer)"	Process for climate informed advice		x	x	62
Stakeholder group on integrated coastal zone management	Process for climate informed advice		x	x	64
"Co-designing and building the way we develop models - parameters etc, (collaborative model development and scenario exploration)"	Process for climate informed advice		x		39
Foresighting exercises	Process for climate informed advice			x	86
"qualitative network modeling to explore change scenarios and their consequences (positive or negative) on individual human activities, ecosystem components (and ultimatly the entire socio-ecological system)"	Process for climate informed advice			x	78
Shared Socio-economic Pathways (SSPs)	Process for climate informed advice			x	67
Precautionary buffers	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x	?		31
"adoption of clear objectives, targets and reference points in fisheries and other sectors"	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x	x		46
Climate informed stock assessments and forecasts	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x	x		30
dynamic management closure areas based on now-casts of temperature based species distributions and bycatch risk	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x	x		29
Assessment models that explores a scaled Fenv.	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x			10
Stock assessment or habitat models with climate covariates	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x			26
summary information by species of biological changes included into traditional advice sheets	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x			23
Tracking of increasing marine transport and new routes	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"	x			20
Current and predicted trends at key variables and pressures	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"		x		57
"minimum biomass thresholds that adjust based on MHW forecasts for the next 1-2 years (e.g., 20%B0)"	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"		x		44
Simulation modeling: blob occurence and intensity (based on available data)	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"		x		54
Species/habitat (specifically blue carbon habitats) distribution maps and projections	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"		x		50
Adaptation strategy assessments	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	94
Counterfactual / retrospective analyses to test policy options (what if in the past we had done... )	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	87
Ecological forecasts and projections	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	70
Fishery depdendence tool	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	76
fleet assessments	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	73
IEA	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	80
Satellite tracking of ice coverage	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	74
Set of scenarios around percentage of restoration under climate change	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	89
temperature projections to adjust area & season closures for upcoming 5 years	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"			x	79
xdynamic management closure areas based on now-casts of temperature based species distributions and bycatch risk	"Stock, habitat, and ecosystem assessments"				11
"xadoption of clear objectives, targets and reference points in fisheries and other sectors"					17
"xCerification, scoring, carbon labeling, ecolabeling"					55
xClimate informed stock assessments and forecasts					53
xEcological forecasts and projections					37
xExecutive summaries					49
xExecutive summaries					77
"xFinancial incentives for technology and gear development (e.g., loans)"					59
"xFinancial incentives for technology and gear development (e.g., loans)"					95
xGaming / scenario exploration					84
xInfographics and maps to help visualise the concepts and uncertainties					41
xInfographics and maps to help visualise the concepts and uncertainties					83
xManagement Strategy Evaluation					56
xMedia & Visualizations					65
xMedia & Visualizations					32
"xminimum biomass thresholds that adjust based on MHW forecasts for the next 1-2 years (e.g., 20%B0)"					38
xParticipatory and co-development scenario planning					68
xParticipatory and co-development scenario planning					43
xPolicy briefs or report cards					66
xPolicy briefs or report cards					33
xScience workshops					92
xScience workshops					35
xSecondary/primary school educational workshops					52
xSecondary/primary school educational workshops					93
xtemperature projections to adjust area & season closures for upcoming 5 years					72
xVisual tools/storytelling/cartoons					42
xVisual tools/storytelling/cartoons					60
xVisual tools/storytelling/cartoons					75
xVisual tools/storytelling/cartoons					91
"xWeb-type portal for displaying evidence, sharing data"					85
					
					7
					2
					3
					34
					69
